天 蝎
</
>
第二季 第二十二集
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
僅供學習 禁止用于任何商業盈利行為
更多影視更新
請登陸www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻譯：雙子草  Carcara  采薇
翻譯：馬云我賜你姨媽  Scar  安sim  Skylet
校對：天蝎坦
時間軸：念念  兜兜兜爹
后期：天蝎斯人     總監：TanKnoX
打開微信   掃描左側二維碼
或搜索公眾號:    美劇炸了
了解最新影視資訊字幕信息
人人留學【免費辦理】
震撼上線，趕快登陸
www.rrliuxue.com
英、澳、日三國免費辦理
眾多美國大學，快捷錄取
人人留學——開啟單向收費新時代
《天蝎》前情提要
Previously on Scorpion...
這位是我的新學員  蒂姆·阿姆斯特朗
Meet my new trainee, Tim Armstrong.
各位好
Hello.
稍微帶有一點不完美的完美
There's nothing more stunning than
是最動人的
seeing perfection with a slight imperfection.
你是個律師
You're a lawyer.
是的
Yes.
這是我的名片
It's my card.
海伍德·賈赫普彌
"Heywood Jahelpme."
這中間名好獨特
That's a unique middle name.
其實  是
Um, actually it's pronounced
賈...赫普彌  就是
"Ja-help-me," As in,
"你好  能幫幫我嗎"
"Hey, would ya help me?"
好吧
Okay, oh, yeah.
真對不起
I'm sorry.
不怎么擅長第一次約會
Not good at first dates.
那次約會并不是我最糟糕的一次
It was not the worst date that I've ever had.
好了
All right, hey, um...
-你想過來嗎  -好  抱歉
- do you want to come through? - Okay, sorry.
-借過  -來  抱歉
- Excuse me. - Here, yeah, sorry.
這個地方很不錯
Here's a good vantage point.
好激動啊
Oh, so excited.
我參加過電影首映  沒看過花首開
Went to a movie opening once, never a flower opening.
不是普通的花  是泰坦魔芋
Oh, not just any flower, the titan arum.
我都沒聽說過這種植物
Never even heard of this plant.
這幾周來跟你在一起
It's one of a million incredible things
我學到了好多不可思議的東西
that I have learned these past weeks
今天又學到一樣
just from spending time with you.
我真的很開心  沃特
I'm really happy, Walter.
我也是
I am as well.
植物園的資助者們
Botanical Gardens patrons,
十年里  泰坦魔芋將在幾分鐘后
the titan arum will be blooming for the first time
首次開花
in a decade in just a moment.
禁止拍照
Photography is prohibited.
要嗎
You want one?
不  謝謝  我還一肚子晚飯吃的烤魚呢
No, thank you, I'm full of fermented fish from dinner.
我也是
Oh, huh, me too.
我真的喜歡上這個了
I'm really getting a taste for it.
印度尼西亞人管它叫尸臭花
Do you know the Indonesians call it bunga bangkai?
就是花加上尸體
So, bunga means flower and bangkai means cadaver.
為什么叫這個
Why do they name it that?
因為開花時它會散發尸臭味兒
Well, 'cause that's what it smells like when it opens.
開花了
Oh, it's blooming.
天吶
Oh, God...
是啊  是不是很神奇
I know, isn't it truly amazing?
琳達
Linda?
洛杉磯縣法院
你帶她去看尸臭花
You took her to see the corpse flower?
她很喜歡的
She loved it...
她還喜歡碳定年系列講座
like she loved the carbon dating lecture series,
格里菲斯天文臺展覽
the Griffith Observatory exhibit...
還有科技中心的
Oh! And the Combustion Motors Pavilion
內燃機館
at the Science Center.
那不是約會  是科學考察
Those aren't dates; those are field trips.
聽著  伙計
Look, pal,
我早就覺得懷疑了
I've been suspicious of something for a while now,
而你的約會證實了我的擔心
and your date confirms my fear.
琳達根本不喜歡你
Linda ain't into you.
你錯了
Wrong.
她很喜歡我的智商
She's very much EQ for my IQ,
懂我意思吧
if you know what I'm saying.
我懂  惡心
I do, and gross...
但事實上  她是有少女綜合征
but the fact is she suffers from Damsel Syndrome.
因為你冒生命危險救了她
'Cause you risked your life to save her,
所以她跟你在一起時
so when she's with you
她又再次體驗了
she experiences the same
那次緊張經歷時
dopamine and endorphin release
釋放多巴胺和腦內啡的情景
she had during that intense experience.
她是迷戀那種身體反應
S-s-she's hooked on that physiological reaction.
而這最終會消退
It's one that will eventually fade.
她是第一個跟我喜好相同的
Well, she's the first non-genius woman
非天才女性
who actually likes the things that I like;
她喜歡跟我在一起
she enjoys being with me...
她是喜歡她腦子里的化學反應
She-she enjoys the chemical reaction in her brain.
我也并不想告訴你這個  伙計
I-I-I take no pleasure in telling you this, pal.
聽著  佩吉最近經常跟蒂姆在一起
Look... Paige has been spending some time with Tim lately.
你的潛意識看到了這個
Your subconscious sees this
就想給自己也找個伴
and wants you to find your own companion.
讓你看不清真相
It's blinding you to the truth.
好啊  你們來了
Good, you guys are here.
凱布不喜歡別人用他的旅行杯
Oh, Cabe doesn't like it when people use his travel mugs.
不  是蒂姆給我的
Oh, no, Tim-Tim gave it to me.
我們進去吧
Okay, should we go in?
你沒事吧  你似乎不舒服
Are you okay? You look sick.
不  我就是
What, no, I'm just...
擔心拉爾夫
uh, anxious about Ralph.
好
Oh, okay.
我堅持讓拉爾夫在我課上用我的電腦
I insisted Ralph work only on my laptop in class
是因為我不確信
because I doubted that
一個孩子能獨立完成所有課業
a child could do all the work on his own without any help.
我是想近距離觀察他
I wanted to observe him closely.
我的擔心是有依據的
My concerns were founded.
他的作業沒能及格
He failed the assignment.
我要打昏他
I'm gonna knock this guy out.
所以你讓他用了你的電腦
So, you had him use your computer,
所以就沒法證明
so there's no real way to prove
是拉爾夫編寫了我們所說的程序
that Ralph created the code in question?!
是啊  我就這意思
Yes, that's my point.
不不不  等等
No, no, no, wait, uh...
我是說
I meant...
他
his, um...
他...法官大人  我能重說嗎
he's turning... Your Honor, can I start over?
希望他有所準備
I hope he's working on contingency.
莫里斯先生  你還有什么問題嗎
Mr. Morris, do you have any more questions at this time?
我不確定
I'm not sure.
這跟我預想的不一樣
This is not going how I'd hoped.
請求提問  法官大人
Request for re-direct, Your Honor?
說吧
Go ahead.
這比電視上演得難多了
This is harder than it is on TV.
教授  能告訴我們這是什么嗎
Professor, can you tell us what these are?
編程就像寫小說
Coding's like writing a novel.
我不想因為電腦故障而丟章節
Don't want to lose chapters to a computer glitch,
所以我有做備份
so I back up my work.
打印文檔證明我已經編寫這些程序六個月之久
The printout proves I've been scripting that code for six months.
我不是最近才偷的
I didn't just recently steal it.
拉爾夫的程序只是很基本的項目
Ralph's code was just a rudimentary project.
他搞砸了
He just messed up.
如果我能拿到記錄  我就能打敗他
If I can get those records, I can beat this guy.
我看夠了  我打算判決了
I've seen enough. I'm ready to rule.
你得阻止他  海伍德
You have to stop him, Heywood.
但他都拿起錘子了
But he's picking up the hammer.
想想辦法
Think of something.
法官大人  我們并未看到過這些備份文件
Your Honor, uh, we've not seen the back up documents ever.
因為你自己沒申請
That's because you never requested them.
你只要了程序的副本
You only asked for a copy of the code,
而沒要編程的過程文件
not the work product that went into making the code.
是啊  那是因為我忘了
Yes... but that's because I forgot.
法官大人
Your Honor,
你現在不能判決
you can't rule at this moment because, uh...
我的委托人有嚴重精神問題
My client has major mental issues.
說誰呢
Talk about projection.
有話快說  莫里斯先生
Make your point, Mr. Morris.
宣誓書中已經表明  我的委托人是名天才
As stated in the affidavits, my client is a genius,
高智商可能是有害的
and high intelligence can be a detriment,
您允許一名有特殊障礙的少年
and you allowed a minor with unique challenges
在進行能力聽證之前就打算做出裁決
to testify before we could give him a competency hearing.
你要質疑你自己委托人的能力
You're challenging the competency of your own client?
你是在拖時間
You're just trying to buy time.
法官大人  如果你現在裁決
Your Honor, if you rule now,
那么我們可以提出上訴
you leave your decision open for appeal...
或者  你可以讓我給他做測評
or, you could let me have him evaluated.
好吧  給你到下午2點
Fine, you have until 2:00 p.m.
好嘞
All right.
拿下一樁動議
Won a motion.
再跟我說一遍你們要
Tell me again what you're looking for
在這一堆文件里找什么
in these boxes of paperwork.
有時候我在我的程序里留下數字線索
Sometimes I'd leave numerical clues in my code
好標記我需要回頭進行修改的地方
to remember where I had to go back to clean things up.
叫做書簽
It's called bookmarking.
叫做"我聽不懂"
It's called, "I'm lost."
我去翻翻案卷
I'm gonna go read case files,
看看能不能找到有用的東西
see if I can find anything to help us.
有人知道鎮子上有法律圖書館嗎
Anybody know if there's a law library in town?
我自己去找吧
I'll find it.
我也搞不懂了
Yeah, uh, I'm lost, too.
書簽怎么會有用
How does bookmarking help?
我用了一些我很容易察覺的數字  比如我生日
I used numbers easy for me to spot, like my birthday.
如果我能找到  就能證明是我做的
So if I find them, I can prove I did the work.
你是個天才
You're a genius;
你不記得把它們放在哪了嗎
don't you remember where you left them?
有兩千五百萬行代碼
There's 25 million lines of code.
如果想的話我本來是可以記住地點的
Could've memorized the locations if I wanted to,
但當時我覺得沒什么必要
but I didn't think it was relevant at the time.
好吧  我去找其他人來
Okay, I'm gonna grab the others
我們一起找找你到底把聲波曲線
and we'll start searching where you scripted the sine curves
寫在哪了
of the sound waves.
不  我用的是逆傳播表面聲波
No, I used counter-propagating surface acoustic waves;
將它們穿透壓電襯底發射
sent them across the piezoelectric substrate.
等等  那要怎么起作用
Wait, how-how does that work?
這樣我就能通過改變音調控制數據流變化
So, I can change data flow by changing sound pitch.
我不確定那會有用
I'm not sure how that would play out.
就是個簡單的數據傳輸
It's simple data transfer.
好吧  是在波峰還是波谷
Right, on-on the crest or the trough of the wave?
你是對的
You're right.
你應該集中在正弦曲線上
You should work on the sine curves.
拉爾夫  我不需要你來教我關注哪個  好嗎
Ralph, I don't need you to tell me what to work on. Okay?
我們先解決聲波的事
We'll focus on the acoustic waves.
沒多少時間了  先做了再說
Now we don't have much time, so let's just get to it.
你到底怎么回事
What the hell is wrong with you?
你吼了他
You snapped at him.
我沒吼
I didn't snap.
不  他解釋過頭了  而我們時間很緊迫
No, he was overexplaining and we're on a clock.
他在幫你解決
He was helping you with something
你根本不了解的事  你卻吼了他
that you clearly didn't understand, and you barked at him.
我沒有  他甚至沒有
I did not. He doesn't even...
有情感
Feel things?
有  他有的  沃特
Yes, he does, Walter.
他和你很像  但不完全一樣
He is like you, but not exactly like you.
你該向他道歉
You owe him an apology,
如果你再用那種態度跟他說話的話
and the next time you talk to him like that,
我就不干了
I am out of here.
沃特
Hey, Walt.
誰惹你了
Who peed in your punch?
什么
What?
沒人惹我
Nobody.
那把大家召集起來
Then gather up the gang.
蒂姆正帶著國防部的庫克探員
Tim's coming in with Agent Cook
往這邊來
from the Department of Defense.
他有最高權限  這些家伙可不喜歡浪費時間
He has top clearance and these guys don't mess around.
諾克斯堡是一處美軍基地
Fort Knox is a U.S. Army base.
檔案影像資料
這里著名的金庫
The famous gold depository located there
由財政部一手控制
is controlled completely by the Treasury.
他們不僅有權控制
They also have authority over
全國的黃金供應情況
not only our nation's gold supply,
還掌握著歷史文物  比如《人權法案》
but artifacts from our history such as the Bill of Rights
以及《獨立宣言》
and Declaration of Independence.
這些文件在華盛頓國家檔案博物館展出
Those are displayed in the National Archive Museum in D.C.
看起來像這些文件的仿品都在特區展出
Documents that look like them are displayed in D.C.
真品都需要被保護起來
The real McCoys need to be protected.
一些政府為了安全起見
Knox also houses historic valuables
也把他們珍貴的歷史文物存在諾克斯
belonging to foreign governments for safekeeping
因為毫無疑問
because the facility is, without question,
那里是地球上最安全的地方
the most secure on earth.
我感覺你接下來要說個很厲害的"但是"
I'm sensing a big "But" Coming.
很厲害的"蛋"
Big butt.
最近
Well, recently,
財政部雇用了斯蒂爾森保全公司
the Treasury privatized Depository security
將金庫的保全系統私有化了
by hiring Steelson Security,
這個公司有點像黑水公司
it's a Blackwater-like firm.
美國著名雇傭兵和安全顧問公司
國防部覺得這威脅到了
The DOD feels this compromises
國家寶藏和金儲備
our nation's treasures and reserves.
我們覺得應該我們保護金庫
We feel we should protect the Depository
也想證明給總統看
and we want to prove it to the president.
好吧  給我們提供基地航拍照片
Okay... provide aerial photos of the base,
私人保全公司的運輸流程細目表
breakdown of the private security company's operational logistic,
我們會分析...
we'll analyze...
不  理論分析太薄弱了
No, I can't use theories.
我需要證據
I need proof...
唯一能證明諾克斯堡并不安全的辦法
and the only way to prove Fort Knox isn't secure...
就是闖進去
is to break in.
說什么瘋話呢
Crazy-man-says-what-now?
除非有真憑實據證明有安全隱患
The White House doesn't want to order a security change
白宮是不會想更換保安系統的
without hard evidence of vulnerability.
如果他們換了
Because if they do,
之后諾克斯又出了問題
and Knox is cracked at a later date,
他們會被唾罵攻擊的
the administration has egg on its face.
沒錯
Exactly.
證明能攻破的證據
Proof of successful breach
是要讓有三百年歷史的普魯士權杖消失
will be the removal of a 300-year-old Prussian scepter
因為德國和波蘭之間存在所有權爭議
held by the U.S. due to an ownership dispute
這支權杖現由美國保管
between Germany and Poland.
世界上獨一無二的權杖
One of a kind,
布滿了完美的寶石  無法造假
covered in flawless diamonds, and can't be forged.
你們把它偷出來
You retrieve it,
然后我們就知道該更改寶藏的安保系統了
we know we have to change the way our assets are protected.
但沒人可以知道我們要這么干
But no one can know that we're coming in
要不這次行動就有先天缺陷了
or the endeavor is inherently flawed.
也就是意味著真正的保安
Which means real guards...
拿著真槍
With real guns...
會想盡辦法阻止我們
Will try to stop us.
沒錯
Yes...
而且這項工作是絕對不會記錄在案的
and the job is completely off the books,
說如果你們被抓到了  國防部和白宮
which means if you're caught, the DOD and the White House
不會承認對這次行動知情
will deny any knowledge of this mission...
即使你們通過了保安
and even if you get past the guards,
一直到達了地下保險庫
all the way to the subterranean vault,
按照設計  一旦有入侵跡象
it's rigged to expel knockout gas
就會釋放窒息性毒氣
at the first sign of tampering,
而且沒人知道保險庫里面還有什么機關
and who knows what traps lay beyond that door.
是啊  我看過類似的電影
Yeah, I've seen this movie before.
史泰龍  測試看看那監獄夠不夠安全
Hey, Stallone, go see if that prison is secure.
指的是史泰龍2013主演的電影《金蟬脫殼》
什么  你被困在里面了
What? You're trapped now?
真不巧
That's a bummer.
抱歉  老兄  不記錄在案我們也不會考慮
Sorry, pal, off the books is off the table.
好吧  但是不記錄也就是不會入賬
All right but off the books means off the ledger,
意味著不用交稅
as in tax-free.
沒錯
All right.
一百萬美元現金
$1 million cash.
總統和國家感謝你們的付出
Compliments of your president and a grateful nation.
我能聞聞嗎
Do you mind if I smell that?
老實說  很誘人
You know what, i-it is very tempting,
但變數太多
but there are too many variables...
而我們不是小白鼠
and we're not lab rats.
把我們關進籠子里看看陷阱能不能起作用
Put us in a cage and see if the trap springs?
還是算了吧
No, thank you.
沒錯  沃特說得對
Yeah, Walter's right.
這幫人不玩碟中諜
These guys, they don't do Mission: Impossible.
光是保險庫里的機械障礙
I mean, the mechanical obstacles they would face
就夠他們受的了
in the vault alone are too daunting.
放松點  舞會國王
Easy... Prom King.
我能破解所有的保險箱
I can figure out any safe.
我很懷疑
Doubtful.
再說了  我們說的是嚴格訓練過的私人雇傭兵
Plus, we're talking about highly-trained private mercenaries.
可不是光靠計謀就能打敗的
They don't just get outsmarted.
我還沒到過看不透或者比我更聰明的人
I have yet to meet a person that I can't read or outsmart.
你襯衫上沾到咖啡漬了  看到了嗎
You got a little coffee stain on your shirt. Oh, see?
智取成功
Outsmarted.
好吧  但諾克斯堡采用了最先進的軟件
Okay, but Fort Knox is run by state-of-the-art software
-破解不了  -多謝
- that can't be cracked. - Thank you.
很高興你提出自己的看法  蒂姆  但
Appreciate the insight, Tim, but, uh...
我們能突破外部建筑
we can handle the physical structure,
解決保安  破解軟件
the guards, the software
搞定所有難關
and anything else that's thrown at us...
但是
oh, but...
拉爾夫需要我們的幫助
Ralph needs our help.
我來幫他  我提供能車庫里的一切幫助
I can help him, and I can provide support from the garage.
我會和拉爾夫參加聽證會  這行得通
I'll be with Ralph for the hearing. This could work.
你同意嗎
You okay with this?
我不喜歡因為困難就放棄
I don't like backing down on something just 'cause it's difficult.
我不喜歡放棄一百萬美元
I don't like backing down from a million dollars.
好好想想  沃特
Think about this, Walt.
我以為我才是刺激他們自尊心的人
I thought I was the one who manipulated their egos.
整個諾克斯都事關國家利益
Knox is an integral national interest,
國安部需要天蝎來接手這個案子
and Homeland needs Scorpion to take this case...
看你的表現
...and I may have picked up a few things
我差不多也學會了一點怎么對付這群人
on how to handle these guys from watching you.
名師出高徒  對吧
Learn from the best, right?
行  侵入諾克斯堡吧
All right, let's break into Fort Knox.
我想說我們可以侵入安全系統
I'd say we could hack the security,
但我覺得諾克斯是沒有接入過網的
but I assume Knox is air-gapped.
沒錯
Yes.
整個系統都是離線的
System's completely off-line.
太棒了  所以這意味著沒有信息
Great, so that means there's no information
進入或者流出金庫
transmitted into or out of the Depository.
但你知道是用什么進出基地的嗎  水
But you know what is transferred in and off the base: water.
那里有很多水管以便水進進出出
There are pipes bringing water in and out.
標準水暖管道大小不足以
Standard plumbing pipes aren't big enough
讓人通過
for humans to fit through.
那還用說嗎  但是它們太小了  容易堵塞
No duh, but they are small enough to easily clog.
我可以用追蹤器改裝玩具潛艇
I can modify a toy submarine with a GPS tracker.
把它放入城市排水系統
Drop it into the municipal system.
希爾在車庫里控制它
Sly controls it from the garage.
諾克斯的藍圖是最高機密
Knox's blueprints are top secret,
但是城市用水圖很容易入侵
but the municipal water schematics are easily hacked.
我可以把潛艇引到金庫下面
I can guide the sub underneath the Depository.
玩具還沒有大到可以形成堵塞
Toy's not big enough to cause a clog.
這就要它運載正確的貨物才行
It is if it's carrying the right cargo.
樂樂  你覺得怎么樣
Happy, what're you thinking?
聚氨酯泡沫塑料
Polyurethane foam.
希爾彈開艙門
Sly pops open the hatch,
當聚氨酯和水起反應時
when polyurethane reacts with water it expands,
地上就會有大量的水溢出
causing a heck of a spill upstairs.
他們就會像基地維修部報告
They'll report the problem to Base Maintenance.
我們侵入他們的電話系統就能接收所有電話
We hack their phone system so all calls come to us.
維修部
Maintenance.
當然  我會馬上派水管工人過去
Sure thing, I'll send a plumbing crew up to you right away.
好  那他們就充當水管工吧
Okay, so they pretend to be plumbers
但是他們怎樣到達基地
but how do they get on the base?
我和蒂姆會解決這個問題
Tim and I can help out with that.
我們通過國土安全部
We set up a meeting
安排了和基地指揮官的會面
with the base commander through Homeland
假借討論像諾克斯那樣的國家機構
under the guise of discussing theoretical threats
理論上所面臨的威脅
against national institutions like Knox.
我們是來見方特諾特上校的
We're here to see Colonel Fontenot.
找到時機我們就會離開車尾箱
We exit the trunk in character.
水管工軍隊準備好來幫忙
Army plumbers ready to lend a hand.
謝謝你們這么快趕到
Thanks for getting here so fast.
那里真是一團糟
It's a real mess in there.
別擔心
No worries.
我們處理過很多混亂的局面
We deal with a lot of messy situations.
一旦在金庫拿到了權杖
Once in the Depository, you get the scepter
就到基地樹林里的會合點和我見面
and meet me at a rendezvous point in the woods on the base.
國防部管理著軍事基地
DOD runs Army bases
所以我可以理所當然地進去
so I can get on the grounds as a matter of course.
但是他們怎么進去保險庫里
But how do they get into the vault?
簡單  我們用他們的安保系統對付他們
Simple, we use their own security system against them.
要知道  我不是在教你怎樣做你的工作
You know, I'm not telling you how to do your job
但那些看起來不像水管
but those don't look like water pipes.
他們看起來像導管
They look like conduit.
要是你看一下栓口你會看水的凝結
If you look at the spigot hole there's condensation.
看到了嗎
Hmm, look at that?
這地方可能有窒息性毒氣
Maybe they do have knockout gas in this place.
樂樂  打開它
Happy, hit it.
然后我把本該通往保險庫門口的毒氣改一下路徑
Then I re-route the gas that was meant for the vault door
通過排氣系統散播開來
so it disperses through the vent system.
窒息性毒氣讓我們有30分鐘時間
Knockout gas gives us 30 minutes
進入保險庫  打開它
to get into the vault, crack it,
拿到權杖迅速離開
grab the scepter and exit.
我和蒂姆完成與上校的談話后
Tim and I finish up our chat with the Colonel,
在車旁等你們
wait for you by the car.
我們已經占用你足夠多的時間了  上校
Well, we've taken up enough of your time, Colonel.
要知道國安部會竭盡所能幫助你們
Just know that Homeland's here to help you any way we can.
我們已經覆蓋了整個基地
Well, I've got the base covered,
自從斯蒂爾森接管以后
don't know much about the Depository
對金庫還不是很了解
since Steelson took over.
唯一的變化是他在保險庫入口加了一名
Only change is they put a fully armed and equipped guard
全副武裝的守衛
down at the vault entrance
而不是只讓守衛在通往保險庫的電梯里守著
instead of just at the elevators leading to it.
真的嗎
You don't say.
沃特  你收到了嗎
Walter, did you copy that?
地下室保險庫不只有毒氣守護
There's more than gas guarding the basement vault.
還有個守衛  沃特
There's a guard, Walter!
是的  我們發現了
Yes, we are aware.
糟了
Not good.
你們全部趴在墻上
All of you, up against the wall!
你會相信我們只是
Would you believe that we're the plumbers
來修水管的水管工嗎
who've come to fix the sink?
看來是不相信
I guess not.
我想他剛剛打了托比
I think he just hit Toby.
別跟他耍花腔
Don't wise-mouth the guy.
按他說的做
Do what he says.
現在趴在墻上
Against the wall now!
好  好
Okay, okay.
我是派克  那邊有人醒來了嗎
This is Pike. Anyone awake up there?
有人收到嗎  重復  收到了嗎
Anyone copy? Repeat, do you copy?
想得美  我的面具有夜視功能
Nice try. My mask has night vision.
正是我們所希望的  手電筒
That's what we're counting on, flashlights.
發生什么事了
What is going on?
他們偷襲了他
They ambushed him.
我想我們抓住他了
I think we got him h-here.
開燈
Turn the lights on.
我抓不住他  你屁股還坐在我臉上
I cannot hold him with your posterior in my face!
好吧  我正在讓他的槍遠離我們
Well, I'm aiming his gun away from us.
樂樂  拿下他的面具
Happy, pull his mask off.
你吃了什么
What have you been eating?!
-好吧  -好  好
- Okay. - Good, good.
他睡覺了
He's gone night-night.
好吧
Okay...
我們只剩不到半小時的時間
we have less than half an hour
但是綽綽有余了
but that should be more than enough.
聽著伙計們  你們繼續和我們保持聯系
Here, guys, you can stay on the comms with us,
但我覺得我們可以的
but I think we're okay.
好
Okay.
在此期間  我們幫拉爾夫贏了這件案子吧
In the meantime, let's get to work helping Ralph win this case.
沒錯
Yeah.
好了  現在空氣干凈了  可以呼吸了
Okay, the air is clean enough to breathe now.
我們從地震儀開始吧
Let's get going with the seismograph.
樂樂  這需要花多長時間
Happy, how long is it gonna take?
要是你不干擾我的話一下子就好了
Not long if you don't distract me.
你沒有告訴她你外出辦事嗎
You didn't tell her you were out on a case?
有  我告訴她了
Hmm? Yeah, I did.
可是那女人還在打電話
And yet the damsel still calls?
她太纏人了
Wow, she's jonesing bad.
她沒有少女綜合癥  她是喜歡我
She does not have Damsel Syndrome. She likes me for me.
我設法獲得我按到正確數字時
I am trying to pick up microscopic tremors
保險銷所發出的微小震動
caused by the lock pins when I hit the right number.
我需要安靜  所以你們閉嘴
I need quiet, so both you damsels shut it.
那是什么
What the heck was that?
這是在基地射程范圍的炮火演練
It's artillery practice at the base firing range.
我們也聽到了
We hear it, too.
這些震動影響了讀數
The vibrations are screwing up my readings.
他們繼續在那里開火的話  我什么都做不了
I can't do my job with them blasting away up there.
希爾  你能幫我們解決嗎
Sly, can you help us out here?
已經侵入了基地的系統
Already in the base's system.
它們不是沒有聯網嗎
I thought they were air-gapped.
諾克斯堡金庫是沒有網
Fort Knox Depository is,
但基地的其他地方是聯機的
but the rest of the base is online and vulnerable
并且容易被我入侵的
to my skills.
基地操作  允許訪問
搞定
Yahtzee!
好  根據他們的測試進度表
Okay, according to their testing schedule,
他們正在安裝一臺新的破擊跑自動發射器
they are setting off a new automated mortar launcher.
大概還需要一個小時
It's gonna be going on for another hour.
你沒有那么長時間了
You don't have that long.
而我只知道四個組合編碼的其中兩個
And I've only got two of the four combination numbers.
猜猜剩下的那兩個
Try guessing the last two.
刻度盤上有100個數字  選兩個數字
There's 100 numbers on the dial, two numbers left--
有一萬種可能
that's 10,000 possibilities.
我們需要停止炮擊
We have to stop the shelling.
凱布  我需要你去阻止一下
Cabe, I need you to make a pit stop
而且  你不會喜歡這樣的
and, uh, you're not gonna like it.
天吶
Oh, boy.
很短
Short.
調整兩英里  準備好發射
Adjust 2 mills and fire when ready.
等一下
Wait.
這是
What in the...
停火  有人進入射程范圍了
Hold your fire-- there's someone on the range.
停火
Hold fire!
來吧
Here we go.
士兵們正端著來復槍向我們沖來
There are soldiers running at us with rifles.
沒錯
Yup.
藏起通訊器  拿出證件
Hide your comms. Get your badge out.
我們要開始耍嘴皮子了
We've got some explaining to do.
怎么了  長官
Problem, Officer?
好了
Got it!
需要搜索的房間很多
There's a lot of rooms to search.
好  我們來縮小范圍
Okay, okay, we'll narrow it down.
根據諾克斯堡建造的年份
So, we'll take the year that Fort Knox was built
和歷史學家提供的黃金儲量
and how much gold historians say was stored here,
判斷每間庫房里有多少
then divide it by how many bars fit into each cell,
然后看一看權杖是
and then consider the year the scepter
哪年被送進保險庫的
was brought to the vault so...
或者看下物品清單
Or we could just check the manifest.
就掛在這里的墻上
It was hanging right here on the wall.
權杖在8號庫房
Scepter's in cell eight.
海伍德
Heywood.
你來了
Wh.. there you are, hey.
拉爾夫在哪
Where's Ralph?
還在和希爾一起找文件
Still searching documents with Sly.
你得再爭取些時間
You have to buy more time.
法官已經非常討厭我了
The judge hates me already.
我要是再拖延時間  他會判我蔑視法庭
If I buy more time, he's gonna find me in contempt.
你能想出辦法的  你是個好律師啊
Well, you'll figure something out. You're a good lawyer.
你今天早上不是也看見了嗎
Were you not in court this morning?
我就是個爛律師
I'm a terrible lawyer.
不對
That's not true.
你真正關心委托人
Y-you care about your clients,
這已經比其他律師強了
that's more than most lawyers.
想一想
Ask yourself:
你為什么選擇成為一名律師
why are you an attorney instead of anything else in the world?
一定有很重要的原因
I know there's an important reason.
我小時候  家里的爐子壞了
Uh... w-when I was a kid our oil burner broke.
超級冷
Our house was freezing.
我媽雇來的修理工越修越壞
The guys my mother hired to fix it just made it worse,
我媽就把他們告上了小額索賠法庭
so, she took them to small claims court.
花了380美元
$380 bucks,
當時那是我們僅有的積蓄
but it was all we had,
她勝訴了
and, uh, she won.
于是
So...
家里又重獲了溫暖
our house was warm once again.
這可能就是我想保護小家伙的原因吧
I guess-I guess that's why I want to protect the little guy, too.
拉爾夫對你來說再小不過了
Well, you don't get more little than Ralph.
做點讓你媽媽自豪的事  好嗎
Go make your mom proud, okay?
我會的
I will.
法警  因藐視法庭罪羈押莫里斯先生
Bailiff, take Mr. Morris into custody for contempt of court.
-我讓你找一名專家  -怎么
- I asked for an expert  -What?!
來證明你委托人的能力
to testify to your client's competency
你卻跟我說什么
and you give me a story about a doctor
有個醫生被困在了諾克斯堡
being stuck in Fort Knox!
你干得不錯  給拉爾夫爭取了時間
You did great; you got Ralph more time.
我不能去縣法庭
I can't go to County.
我在那兒給不少人打輸了官司
I lost a bunch of cases for guys in there.
得讓托比來作證  你們得叫托比回來
We need Toby to testify! You got to get Toby back in here!
你確定這下面有壓力板嗎
Are you sure it's on a pressure plate?
里面的凸起正好就在外固定上面
See how the interior ridge is just above the outer frame?
這是因為彈簧
Well, that's 'cause the springs are compressed
被權杖的重量壓了下去
by the weight of the scepter.
一旦拿起權杖  就會發生不好的事情
Okay... we lift it, something bad happens.
這地方誰設計的  007里面的反派么
Who built this place, a Bond villain?
我們能做到
We can do it.
真的  你覺得你能搞定
Really? What makes you think
印第安納·瓊斯都搞不定的機關嗎
you can handle a switcheroo Indiana Jones couldn't pull off?
一塊巨石差點把他碾成肉醬
A giant boulder almost crushed him.
印第安納·瓊斯是誰  某州參議員么
Who's Indiana Jones? A state senator?
我是名機械師
I am a mechanic.
這輩子都在跟重量和測算打交道
I spend my life eyeballing weights and measures.
希爾  你看見權杖了嗎
Sly, you got eyes on the scepter?
已經在計算它的重量
Already calculating its weight.
德國與波蘭因珍貴文物歸屬問題產生爭執
圓柱體積πr2×h
The volume of a cylinder is pi-r-squared times height.
上面球的體積4/3πr3
The spherical top is four-thirds pi-r-cubed.
黃金重量是個常數
The weight of gold is a constant, and, uh,
珠寶的重量就需要猜了
I'm gonna have to guestimate on the jewels
但我會盡量猜得準一點
but I'm gonna be close...
共2.8千克
six pounds, four ounces.
這樣應該可以了
Okay, that should do it.
確定嗎
You sure?
我了解工具
I know tools.
它們的重量的誤差是非常細微的
They'll match the weight within a fraction of an ounce.
好吧  數三下
Okay, on three.
一
One...
二
Two...
三
Three!
看見沒有  諾克斯堡
Take that, Fort Knox.
應該叫你"別想阻止
It's more like Fort Not..
我們這些天才的腳步堡"
Gonna Stop Us 'Cause We're Geniuses...
糟糕了
That's a problem.
怎么了
What's going on?
可別是塊大石頭啊
Please, don't be a boulder.
好吧  這比石頭嚴重多了
All right, that-that is worse than a boulder.
水肯定是從某個儲水槽過來的
They must be feeding a pipe from a storage tank
水量應該剛好能
that is just enough water
沒過整個房間淹死我們
to fill the room and kill us.
這應該就是庫克提醒我們的
I guess this is one of the unknown traps
未知陷阱之一了
that Cook warned us about!
我們怎么觸發這個的
Okay, how did we trip this thing?
我們的計算不會有錯啊
Our calculations were perfect!
沒時間想了
There's not enough time!
來  過來
Here, here! Come here!
水在增加
The water's filling.
來幫我開門
Come help me with the door.
有個水淹陷阱
There's a water trap in there?
伙計們  那房間非常小
Guys, that room is incredibly small.
水流進去的速度有多快
How fast is the water entering?
快到能淹死人了
Fast enough!
這門打不開
This thing isn't budging.
沒法從這里出去了
We can't get out this way.
得想辦法堵住進水口
We've got to find something to stop up the hole.
不  就讓水流進去
No, let the water in!
水充滿整個房間后
With the door straining
門會承受水壓
against the pressure of a room full of water
就容易打開了
it'll be vulnerable.
他說得對
He's right!
阿基米德杠桿原理
It's Archimedes' Law of the Lever.
當施加動力的位置
If the distance from the fulcrum
到支點的距離
to where the input force is applied is greater than
比阻力施加的位置
the distance from the fulcrum
到支點的距離要長時
to where the output force is applied,
動力就會被增強
then the lever amplifies the input force.
所以我們需要一根撬棍是嗎
You're saying we need a crowbar?
沒錯  趕快找
Yes, exactly! Start looking!
希曼之劍可以嗎
Would He-Man's sword work?
那些紋路說明這是大馬士革鋼
These wavy patterns indicate Damascus steel,
最堅硬的金屬之一
some of the toughest in history.
好的  一起拉
Okay, okay, let's pull together.
還是紋絲不動
This thing isn't budging.
有人感到水里有一絲暖意嗎
If anyone notices the water getting warmer,
那只是因為我嚇尿了而已
it's just 'cause I'm scared.
加油  伙計們  你們做得到
Come on, guys, you can do this.
好
Okay.
聽我數
On my count!
吸最后一口氣
We take one last breath... Okay.
然后一起使出全力  好嗎
...and then we give it everything we got! Okay?
都還好嗎
Everyone okay?
好  樂樂呢
Good. Happy?
不能更好
Never better.
門終于松動了
Okay, the door's compromised.
我們現在可以打開它了
Now we can open it and beat it.
好  雖然門外的警衛已經暈了
Good, 'cause the guards here might be passed out
但斯蒂爾森公司總部
but no way an alarm wasn't tripped
肯定也已經收到了警報
to Steelson headquarters.
隨時會派人來
There's gonna be men here any minute.
我不可能算錯了重量
I know I had the weight right.
超級天才也會犯錯
Mistakes happen, even to super geniuses.
不對  這東西感覺不像2.8千克
Not this one. This doesn't feel like six pounds.
它很輕
It's light.
那就是他們不再像以前那樣做權杖了
Well, they don't make scepters like they used to.
伙計們  有問題
Guys... we've got a problem.
這個問題更大
Not as big as this one!
他們進不來了
Now they can't get in.
我們也出不去了
And we can't get out.
即使他們從上級那里獲得密碼
Even if they get the combo from their superiors,
齒輪也會被卡住  這樣可以拖住他們
the gears will be jammed. That should slow them down.
好的  我們走
Good, let's go.
現在我們來考慮這瓶東西
Now let's focus on that vial,
考慮到庫克派我們來的原因  我要指出一點
AKA the real reason Cook sent us in here and let me point out,
是我提到了史泰龍電影里
it was I who referenced the Stallone film
英雄們被巨石壓倒
where the heroes get screwed.
還有人記得嗎
Does everyone remember that?
這像是一種粉塵  一種粉末
It's like a dust, like a powder.
是的  閃著銀光
Yeah, it's silvery,
一種銀灰色的粉末
it's-it's gray with a shimmer.
把它藏起來的人選擇了金子
Whoever hid this chose gold.
金子適合屏蔽輻射
Gold's good at shielding radiation.
我覺得我手中拿的是釙
I think I'm holding polonium.
趕緊放下
Put that down.
這就是殺死了脫離克格勃的
That's what killed the MI6 agent
軍情六處特工的罪魁禍首
that defected from the KGB.
沃特  這東西可是劇毒物
Walt, this stuff is crazy toxic.
一克可以殺死一千萬人
One gram can kill ten million people.
好的
Okay...
只要我們不攝入它就沒事
we're safe as long as we don't ingest it.
這應該有半斤
There's got to be half a pound here.
那足以消滅世界上四分之一的人口
That could wipe out a quarter of the world's population.
想象一下北京高層下令用噴粉飛機
Imagine this dispersed from a crop duster in the Midwest,
把這個灑在中西部地區
from the top of a skyscraper in Beijing.
庫克探員瞞著我們這一點
Agent Cook would only keep this from us
很可能因為他想用這一瓶做壞事
if he had bad plans for this vial.
希爾  我需要你調查一下庫克
Sly, I need you to look into Cook.
問問凱布  看看他是否能提供這家伙的背景
Talk to Cabe, see if he can give you any background on the guy.
我正在試著與他聯系
I've been trying to get in touch with him
但是他并沒有回應
but his comms aren't in.
好的
Okay.
與上校核實過了
Everything checks out with the Colonel.
這件事說起來很不好意思
Yeah... really embarrassed by all this.
我們
We, uh...
在路口轉錯了彎
just took a wrong turn on an access road,
沒有找到出口反而闖進了這里
wound up out here instead of heading toward the exit.
是的
Yes, sir.
現在你需要趕快找到出口
Well, now you need to find that exit
因為你延誤了我們的訓練
because you've delayed our training.
了解
Understood.
讓我們離開這
Let's get out of here.
凱布  你在哪
Cabe, where are you?
我在呢
All right, I'm here.
我們快成功了嗎
Are we almost wrapped up?
我們碰到了點問題
Well, we hit a speed bump.
我們過不去的
We're not getting through it.
如果我們順著管子到達儲水箱
If we follow the pipe to the reservoir tank
我們有可能離開這里
we might get out of here.
那些士兵切開保險庫門
It's only a matter of time before Steelson
只是時間問題
cuts through that vault door.
就是這個  我們把鋼條切開
That's it. We cut through the bars.
你的工具箱里有個標準的切管器
You have a standard pipe cutter in the tool box.
但是它切不開鋼條
It's not getting through steel.
給它裝上金剛石刀片就可以
It will with a diamond blade.
我走了四個街區去法院
I go four blocks to the courthouse and
結果麻煩接踵而至
all hell breaks loose.
可不是嗎  但是現在沒工夫討論這個
Apparently, but I can't discuss it right now
因為我正在收集庫克的信息
because I am gathering info on Cook.
沃特  你們快出來了嗎
Walter, you guys close to breaking out?
快了
Getting there.
他們也是
So are they.
他們切割的速度很快
They're cutting through pretty quick.
佩吉  我們一會兒會進入管道中
Paige, we'll be in the pipe in moments.
我們沒問題的
We're okay, we got this.
好的  保持聯絡
All right, well, keep us posted.
搞定
Got it.
托比  快過來
Toby, get down here!
我們要走了
We're leaving!
快點
Come on!
沃特  我們快到集合點了
Walter, we're almost at the rendezvous.
你們在哪
What's your 20?
今天第二次了
For the second time today,
再次非常靠近托比的屁股
very close to Toby's backside.
可能和釙一樣有毒
Could be as toxic as the polonium.
有件事  我調查不了庫克
About that, I can't look into Cook because
因為我不知道他的朋友是誰
I don't know who his friends are
而且我不想讓他知道
and I don't want to tip him off
我們發現了他的寶藏
that we found his hidden treasure.
聲音開始有回響了
Voices are starting to echo.
說明這里是開放式的
Means there's an open chamber.
好的  水就是從這來的
Okay. This is where the water came from.
這一定是他們用來向水箱灌水的艙口
Must be a hatch they use to fill the tank, right?
只是個閥門
It's just a valve.
從它的尺寸來看
Judging from the size of it,
我猜他們通過把管子
I'm guessing they fill this thing with a hose
接到液罐車來進行儲水
connected to a tanker truck.
太好了  所以我們爬進了一個死胡同
Oh, great. So we crawled into a dead end.
這個水箱埋在地下
This tank is buried underground.
他們快進來了
They're almost in.
至少我們已經深埋地下六尺了
Well, at least we're already six feet under.
省去了埋葬的時間了
It saves time with the burying.
從我們爬行的距離和角度判斷
From the distance and angle at which we crawled
我估測更像是地下三尺左右
I would estimate more like three feet underground.
謝謝糾正
Oh, thanks for clearing that up.
我可不想我在世上最后的話
I wouldn't want my last words on earth
是一句毫無意義的數學失誤
to be a meaningless mathematical error.
并不是毫無意義  它是有意義的
It's not meaningless. It's meaningful.
這三尺可以改變一切
That three feet makes all the difference in the world.
凱布
Cabe?
你離射擊場有多遠
How far are you from the artillery range?
我需要你征用一臺迫擊炮
I need you to commandeer a mortar launcher.
什么
What?!
這是不可能的  孩子
That's a no-go, son.
我已經離開基地了
I'm already off the base,
而且我很慶幸我離開了因為你已經失去理智了
and I'm glad I am because you've lost your mind.
實際上  在不在基地沒有關系
Actually, being on the base doesn't matter.
在野戰炮部隊里  我仔細觀察了他們的設備
At the artillery field, I got a good look at their equipment.
其中一些迫擊炮  它們是自動的
Some of those launchers, they're automated.
它們可能十分容易被黑客入侵
That makes them potentially vulnerable to hackers.
如果黑了進去  對我們來說就不是"可能"了
When it comes to hacking, there's no "Potentially" with us.
你要武器想干什么
What do you need this weapon for?
我要把這個水箱炸個洞出來
To blow a hole in this tank.
真有意思  等一下
That's funny. For a second,
我覺得他在說向我們自己射一發炮彈
I thought he was suggesting they drop a bomb on us.
標準的迫擊炮彈  地下三尺
Standard mortar round, three feet of dirt,
板寸厚的鋼板  可能會行得通
half inch steel tank... it might work.
可能會殺了我們
Might kill us.
好的  我進去了
Okay, I'm in.
我控制了一臺迫擊炮
I have control of one of the mortar launchers.
守衛現在在保險庫
The guards are in the vault now.
他們隨時會抓到我們
They'll be on us in any minute.
希爾  我們從保險庫
Sly, we crawled about 60 feet
以七度角
at a seven degree incline
爬了大約18米  所以
from the vault room, so...
查一下地圖  估測一下坐標
Check a map and estimate the coordinates
然后發射迫擊炮
and fire that mortar.
好的
Okay...
但是我可能不會精確射中
but I'm not gonna be exact on this.
發射
這不是你想估測就能估測的事情
This is not something you want to estimate.
這不是你能估測的事情
This is not something you estimate!
我能聽見守衛進入管道了
I can hear the guards entering the pipe.
趕快發射炮彈
Launch the mortar now.
好的
Okay.
沒事的
Here goes nothing.
來了
Incoming.
發射
他發射了  我們進入管道里
He launched it, let's get in the pipe.
是琳達嗎
Is that Linda?
你在逗我嗎
You kidding me?
沃特  你聽得見嗎
Walter, can you hear me?!
說話  孩子
Speak up, son.
你讓我們很擔心
You're making us nervous over here.
我們沒事
We're okay.
謝天謝地
Oh, thank God.
這些家伙瘋了
These guys are insane.
這些家伙要讓我突發心臟病了
These guys are gonna give me a heart attack.
看到我的影子了
Oh, it's my shadow.
冬天還有6周才會過完
Six more weeks of winter.
他在模仿美國的土撥鼠日  人們相信
如果土撥鼠出洞看到了自己影子  春天還有6周才會來
別想冬天還有6周的事情了
Forget six weeks of winter.
如果我們動作不快點的話
If we don't hurry
就要在監獄里蹲20年甚至一輩子了
it'll be 20 to life in prison!
快點  我們走吧
Come on, let's go!
站住
Freeze!
沃特  我找到了一些庫克的經歷
Walter, I found something on Cook.
發到你的手機里了
I'm sending it to your phone.
希爾  我現在可沒空看
Little busy now, Sly!
沃特  你必須要看一看
Walter... you need to see this.
跟我們說說
Download us...
重點內容吧
bullet points!
我黑進了他在情報機關的記錄
I hacked his intelligence service record.
27年前  庫克是一名
27 years ago, Cook was
在東德工作的美國秘密探員
a secret U.S. Operative in East Germany.
他的一個聯系人參與了東德的
One of his contacts included
大規模殺傷性武器計劃
a man in a WMD program
探員履歷記錄
那個人的專長就是放射性武器
in East Germany, and his specialty was radioactive weaponry.
當柏林墻被推倒的時候  他出于安全的考慮
When the wall came down, he hid his radioactive material
把放射性物質藏在了權杖里
in the scepter figuring what could be safer.
在波蘭聲稱權杖本應歸他們所有的時候
And when Poland claimed the piece was originally theirs,
權杖和它里面的物品就被轉移到了諾克斯堡
then the scepter and its contents made its way to Fort Knox.
自然界中存在的釙極其稀少
Polonium is incredibly rare in nature.
想買都買不到
You can't get your hands on this stuff.
釙在黑市上的需求一定非常龐大
Black market must be huge.
所以庫克發現了
So Cook saw an opportunity
諾克斯改變安保安排的機會
in the security change at Knox,
他打算乘虛而入
and he jumped at it.
好了
Okay.
我覺得我們暫時甩掉他們了
I think we lost them but not for long.
好了  讓我們整理一下現在是什么情況
All right, let's get our bearings.
天啊  庫克來了
Oh, man, that's Cook.
我們有麻煩了
That's a problem.
他想拿到這個大規模殺傷性武器
Uh, he's gonna want this weapon of mass destruction.
我們該怎么辦
What do we do?
我有辦法
I have a plan.
你們在里面到底做了什么
What the hell did you guys do back there?
整個基地都戒嚴了
The whole place is lit up.
你們拿到權杖了嗎
Did you get the scepter?
拿到了  樂樂  給他吧
We did. Happy, give it to him.
做得不錯  天蝎團隊
Good work, Scorpion.
祖國對于你們出色的表現表示感謝
Your country thanks you for a job well done.
如果我是你的話  我會趕緊逃走
Now I'd get lost if I were you.
等一下
W-wait, uh...
這里還有一顆鉆石
you forgot a diamond.
有點臟了
It's a little smudged,
因為我們用它切割金屬來著
'cause, uh, we used it to cut through steel.
好吧
Okay.
你們剛剛放走的這個人
You guys just let a man
他攜帶的放射性物質
go with enough radioactive material
足以毀掉一整片大陸
to take out a continent.
希望你的計劃能成功
I hope you know what you're doing.
我也是
Me, too.
大家都聽著
Guys, listen up,
托比  我需要兩個松果
So, Toby, I need two pinecones,
樂樂  我需要一些火藥
and, Happy, I need gunpowder.
這些是我能找到的
These are the biggest pinecones I could find
帶有樹脂的最大的松果了
with sap on them.
應該可以黏住火藥了
Should be sticky enough to hold the gunpowder.
蒂姆給了你幾顆子彈
How many bullets did Tim give you?
6顆  足夠了
Six, more than enough.
你看到蒂姆和凱布了嗎
Do you see Tim and Cabe?
沒  他們已經藏好了
No, they're well hidden.
我們這么做太蠢了
This is dumb.
再闖一次諾克斯已經夠瘋狂了
The idea of breaking back into Knox is crazy enough
還要等在這里  試圖干掉那些
but waiting here in the hopes we can take out
追我們的警衛  這簡直是異想天開
those guards on our tail is wishful thinking.
如果我們現在跑到樹林里
If we run into the woods now
被他們抓住  一切就都完了
and get caught, it's over.
在這里等是值得的
It's worth the wait.
好了  別說了  他們來了
Anyway, shut up, they're here.
車在啟動狀態
It's running.
這也許是他們用來逃跑的車
Maybe this was their getaway car,
但是他們在樹林里沒找到
but they couldn't find it in the woods.
我要上報了
I'm calling it in.
抱歉  我還以為這里可以停車呢
Sorry, thought I could park here.
比窒息性毒氣還管用
Better than knockout gas.
樹林安全了  出來吧
Woods are clear. Get moving.
收到
Copy that.
軍警要去調查保險庫  已經上路了
MP's are on the way to investigate the vault.
保持高度警惕
Remain on high alert.
遵命
Yes, sir.
好了  把打火機給我
Okay, give me the lighter.
這個計劃太瘋狂了[直譯為是堅果]
This plan is nuts.
準確地說  這個計劃是種子
Actually, the plan is seeds.
種子經過加熱會炸裂  發出開槍一樣的聲音
When the seeds heat up they will pop like gunfire.
相信我吧
Trust me.
叫我怎么相信一個剛剛用了
How can I trust someone
有關堅果和種子的雙關語的人
who just made a nuts and seeds pun?
好了
Okay.
拿著這個
Hold that.
10點鐘方向有槍聲
Gunfire at 10:00!
有多個射手  快散開
Multiple shooters! Spread out!
快散開
Fan out!
這是老師給你的校園通行證
Here's your hall pass.
別讓校長抓到你
Don't let the principal catch you.
我發誓我帶了證件  聽著
I swear I had it. Look...
我是國防部的
I'm DOD.
列兵戴維斯  這里是正門
Private Davis, Main Gate.
他現在就在這里
He's here with me now.
明白了
Understood.
我可以走了吧
So, it's squared away?
庫克探員  你被捕了
Agent Cook, you're under arrest.
把手放在方向盤上
Hands on the wheel.
等一下
Hold on!
你們弄錯了
This is a mistake!
把手放在方向盤上
Hands on the wheel!
他們在保險庫里找到了你的證件
Your ID's been found... in the vault.
先生
Sir...
那些混蛋
Those bastards.
狄寧女士
Ms. Dineen,
你有沒有讓你兒子去做能力評估
have you had your son evaluated for competency?
有的  法官大人
Yes, Your Honor.
柯蒂斯醫生這里有完整的報告
Dr. Curtis here has a full report.
行了
Hep.
柯蒂斯先生  你是一個真正的醫生嗎
Mr. Curtis, are you a real doctor?
哈佛醫學院畢業  碩士學位
Harvard Medical School with a Masters in...
行了  這個孩子有足夠的能力嗎
Hep. Is the kid competent?
當然了
Absolutely.
這件事我從一開始就知道了
A fact I was well aware of from the outset.
他的律師在哪兒呢
Where is his counsel?
我在這兒呢  法官大人
I'm right here, Your Honor.
我被關起來之后
Since I was incarcerated,
還沒有機會跟我的客戶對話
I didn't have a chance to confer with my client.
給你十秒鐘把要說的說了
Ten seconds, then get to it.
我是準備好了呢
Will I seem like a prepared lawyer
還是沒有準備好
or an ill-prepared lawyer?
準備好了
Prepared.
太好了
Sweet.
拉爾夫  你已經把這份
Ralph, you had the opportunity to review the work product
教授聲稱是他原創的代碼  重新審評過了
that your professor claims is his own.
是的
I did.
跟我說說你發現了什么
Tell me what you uncovered.
我會同時編寫并修改代碼的方方面面
I work on and revise many aspects of the code at the same time,
為了方便查找  我會用特別的日期做書簽
so to keep from getting lost I use bookmarks, specific dates.
拉爾夫  你可以支出這些占位符嗎
Ralph, can you point out these placeholders?
法官大人  我反對
Objection, Your Honor.
我的客戶也會用書簽
My client uses bookmarks as well.
根本沒辦法證明是這個孩子寫了那些書簽
There's no way to prove anything in there came from this child.
我可以證明
I can prove it.
反對無效
Overruled.
繼續說
Go ahead.
我會使用那些對我來說很重要的日期
I use dates that are important to me.
首先是我的生日  2005年12月11日
The first here is my birthday, 12-11-2005,
這個日子很重要是因為我很喜歡我的生活
important because I enjoy my life.
出生證明  已經蓋章并做了公證
Birth certificate, stamped and certified,
完全按規章制度辦事
like it totally should be.
在這個日期的下面
Directly under it,
是1986年4月13日
4-13-1986,
我媽媽的生日
my mom's birthday.
這個日期很重要是因為她是最棒的媽媽
Important because her mothering instincts are superlative.
這是她的駕照
Her license.
我今天的表現棒棒的
Really on my game today.
那一頁上面的日期是
And on that page,
2014年9月22日
9-22-2014,
我和沃特·奧布萊恩初次相遇的日子
the day I first met Walter O'Brien.
這個日子很重要
That's important
是因為那一天我意識到自己不再孤獨
because it's the day I realized I wasn't alone.
他告訴我世上有人和我一樣
He taught me there were others like me
也有人關心我
who cared about me.
我可以證明這個日期
I can verify that date with, uh,
我有一張尼莫斯餐廳老板開的發票
an invoice from the owner of Nemos Diner
我在那里修路由器時第一次遇見了
where I was fixing a router and when I first met Ms. Dineen
狄寧女士和她了不起的兒子拉爾夫
and her amazing son, Ralph.
我沒問你
I didn't ask.
好吧  就是
Okay, it's just, uh...
那也是我人生中非常重要的一天
...it was a very important day in my life, too.
我準備見好就收
I'm gonna quit while I'm ahead.
被告  還有問題嗎
Defense, any cross?
目前沒有
We have nothing at this time.
那我要作出裁決了
Then I have a ruling.
你的委托人應該為自己感到羞恥
Your client should be ashamed of himself.
我判原告獲勝
I rule in favor of Plaintiff.
他敲了小錘子判我贏了
He hit the little hammer in my favor.
這是人生第一次
It's the first time ever.
我贏了
I'm a winner!
我一直在想法官會把我們傳回去改判
I keep thinking the judge is gonna call and reverse the decision,
但是這不合法
but it's not legal.
我查過了
I checked.
你做得很棒
You did an amazing job.
謝了
Oh, thanks.
你們這些人真是太贊了
You have a really fantastic group of people here.
你們支持我  寬容我
Supportive... forgiving.
我只想感謝你
Um, and I just wanted to thank you for...
是你們讓我相信自己
for helping me believe in myself.
你應該相信自己
You should.
你是個很好的律師
You're... a really good lawyer.
謝謝
Thank you.
是我媽媽
Oh, it's my mom.
媽媽  我贏了
Yeah, hi, Mom. Yeah, I won.
是啊  我也不敢相信
Uh-huh, yeah, I can't believe it either.
伙計
Hey, buddy.
你把我們相遇的日子寫進代碼
It means a lot to me
這對我意義重大
that you put the day that we first met in your code.
真抱歉之前對你不耐煩
I'm sorry for being curt with you before.
沒關系的
It's okay.
不  有關系
No, it's not.
我
I, um...
我不會再這樣了
it won't happen again.
但是我相信我說過的話
I do, though, believe in what I said.
好吧
Okay.
我不能理解
I couldn't understand
你那些特別復雜的代碼的具體內容
the details in your incredibly complex code.
我以前以為
I used to think that I-I had
我的智商是全世界第四高的
the fourth highest IQ in the world,
但是現在我明白你把我擠到第五名了
but now I realized that you have dropped me down to number five.
你是因為這個才不開心
That's what got you upset?
不是的
No.
我只是怕你愿意為我而放慢腳步
No, what upset me is that you were willing to slow down
讓我一直錯下去
for me to-to let me go down the wrong road,
因為我不能理解你的作品
when that would've hindered you,
而拖了你的后腿
because I couldn't grasp your work.
永遠不要讓任何人成為你智商的牽絆
Never hobble your intelligence for anyone...
如果你在這個車庫里都要妥協
because if you do that in this garage,
想想你在外面的世界里
imagine what you'll have to do out there...
會為普通人妥協多少
for humans.
這個世界需要跟上你的思路
The world needs to catch up to you...
因為你想想看  只要他們跟上一點點
because if-if it can, just a little,
這個世界
imagine what a...
就會變得更加美好
a beautiful place it could be.
沃特
Hey, Walter.
有人來找你了
You have a visitor.
琳達
Linda...
謝謝你來這兒找我
Um, thanks for meeting me here.
你準備好了嗎
You... are you ready?
這個派對看著很有趣呢
Looks like a fun party.
我們留下也行
We can stay.
你先吃完盤里的東西吧
You can finish your plate.
是的  墨西哥辣卷
Oh, yes, the, uh, the jalapeno poppers.
實際上  墨西哥辣椒中的辣椒素
They're... actually, the capsaicin in the jalapeno
很有益健康
has many health benefits.
真不錯  我嘗嘗
Cool, I'll give one a shot.
不行  不行
Oh, no, no, no!
面糊里有玉米的
There's corn in the batter, yeah.
我記得第一次約會的時候
Yeah, uh, I-I remember on our first date
你說過對玉米過敏
you said you were allergic.
你以為我自己知道呢
Yeah, you think I would know that.
是啊
Yeah.
其實  我確實知道
Uh, actually, I did know that.
但是你還要吃
But you were gonna eat it anyway?
我猜是你讓我變得熱愛冒險了吧
Guess you make me adventurous.
琳達  問你個問題可以嗎
Linda, may I ask you a question?
當然可以
Of course.
你是真的喜歡我
Do you really like me?
還是因為在我身邊
Or does being around me
讓你想起我救你時候的感覺
remind you of a sense memory when you were saved,
你真正喜歡的是這種感覺
and that's what you, uh, really like?
是不是  因為我覺得是后者
Is... because I-I think it's the latter.
這太荒唐了
That's crazy.
是嗎
Is it?
你是不是
Is, um...
你真的喜歡咸魚和
do you really like fermented fish and-and,
臭花嗎
uh, smelly flowers?
你喜歡我這種
D-Do you like a guy
喜歡這種東西的人嗎
who likes those-those kind of things?
我不好說
I'm not sure.
怪不得
it would explain how I sat
我可以耐著性子看完那個非洲蜂遷移的紀錄片
through that documentary on African bee migration.
我是說  你不是真心喜歡我也沒關系的
Well, that's, uh, it's-it's okay that you don't really like me.
但是 你此時此刻為我所做的一切
But... what you're doing for me
讓我...喜歡你
right now makes me... like you.
只是不是那種喜歡
Just not in-in that kind of way.
沒關系的  沒關系的
It's okay, it's okay.
我能理解
I understand.
我們還是朋友嗎
Still friends?
我們永遠都是朋友
Always friends.
好吧
Oh, yeah.
再見了  智多星
Good-bye, smarty-pants.
我只是想來道別
I just wanted to say bye.
我要趕去西雅圖的航班
I'm getting on a plane going to Seattle,
找專家看我的后背
uh, see a specialist about my back,
希望能痊愈復職
hopefully get cleared for duty.
祝你一切順利
Oh. I hope that works out for you.
我也希望
Me, too. Um,
不管結果如何  我想回來以后
Regardless, I was thinking when I got back,
我們可以一起出去吃頓飯嗎
maybe you and I could get a meal together...
去餐廳
at a restaurant --
正式的餐廳  不是科沃斯基那種
a real restaurant, not Kovelsky's.
就像
Oh, like a...
-約會那種  -約會嗎  就是
- date? - Date, yes.
我不強求
Only if you'd like.
我很愿意
Yeah, I would love to.
太好了
Great.
你看他們  他和她
Would you look at them? He's dealing with her, she's dealing with him,
她和才應該在一起  真是白癡
and they should be dealing with each other. They're morons.
我們才不會這樣  我們保持隨意對吧
That's never gonna be us -- we keep it easy, right?
我手最笨了  不好意思
King Klutz over here, I'm sorry.
沒事  醫生  我死不了
Okay, Doc, I'll live.
我去拿點鱷梨醬和薯片
I'm grab us some, uh, guac and chips.
你要確定算對了
Make sure you get it right.
有了這塊水漬  我五分鐘
With this stain, I can extrapolate
就能估算出她的戒指尺寸
her ring size in five minutes.
隨意一點就好
Just keeping it easy.